rover.com 2015-03-18

# Privacy Policy | Rover.com Dog Boarding

Updated March 28, 2014 [Previous versions: April 20, 2012; July 21, 2011; November 14th, 2011].

A Place for Rover, Inc. ("Rover.com," "we," "our,” or "us") provides this Privacy Policy to inform you of our policies and procedures regarding the collection, use and disclosure of Personal Information (as defined below) we receive from users of www.rover.com (this "Site"). At Rover.com, we understand that you value your privacy, and we want to help make your experience with our Site and other services we may offer (referred to in this policy collectively as our “Service”) satisfying and safe. This Privacy Policy applies only to information that you provide to us through this Site. This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time. We may update this privacy statement to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by posting the revised policy on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices. Unless otherwise defined in this Privacy Policy, terms used in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as in our Terms of Service.

As used in this policy, the terms "using" and "processing" information include using cookies on a computer, subjecting the information to statistical or other analysis and using or handling information in any way, including, but not limited to collecting, storing, evaluating, modifying, deleting, using, combining, disclosing and transferring information within our organization or among our affiliates within the United States.

## 1\. Information Collection and Use

Our primary goals in collecting information are to provide and improve our Site, our Services, features and content, and to enable users to enjoy and easily navigate the Site.

## 2\. Personally Identifiable Information

When you register with us through the Site and become a Rover.com Member, when you choose to post or reserve a listing, or when you contact a Rover.com Member using the “Contact” feature of the Site, we will collect personally identifiable information. This refers to information about you that can be used to contact or identify you ("Identity Information"). Identity Information includes, but is not limited to, your name, phone number, email address and home postal address, but does not include your credit card number or billing information. In order to process some of your transactions through the Site, we may also ask for your credit card number and billing information ("Billing Information") (Identity Information and Billing Information together, "Personal Information"). However, if the address of a listing you post matches that of your credit card billing address, that address would be considered Identity Information.

We also collect the other information that you provide as part of registration and the administration and personalization of your profile webpage (e.g., without limitation, zip code (on its own) and individual preferences or demographic information) ("Non-Identifying Information"). Non-Identifying Information includes Personal Information that we aggregate or otherwise render anonymous.

We use your Personal Information (in some cases, in conjunction with your Non-Identifying Information) mainly to provide the Service, complete your transactions, and administer your inquiries. We may use your Personal Information (and disclose it to third parties) to verify your identity, derive other information about you, for fraud prevention, to enforce the terms of the Terms of Service and otherwise protect the integrity of our Site or Service, or to verify other information you provided to us or included in your profile, including for example any associations, certifications, or other attributes of your profile. We may also verify your profile information through other means.

We also use your Personal Information to contact you with Rover.com newsletters, marketing or promotional materials and other information that may be of interest to you. If you decide at any time that you no longer wish to receive such communications from us, please follow the unsubscribe instructions provided in any of the communications or update your "user preferences" information. (See "Changing or Deleting Information," below.) Please note that we may also use your Personal Information to contact you with information related to your use of the Service; you may not opt out of these notifications.

We may use and disclose your Identity Information to third parties for advertising and promotional purposes, but never for directing marketing purposes without your consent. (See Section 11, below, for more information regarding such use and disclosures to third parties.)

## 3\. Log Data

When you visit the Site, whether as Rover.com Member or a non-registered user just browsing (any of these, a "Rover.com User"), our servers automatically record information that your browser sends whenever you visit a website ("Log Data"). This Log Data may include information such as your computer's Internet Protocol ("IP") address, browser type or the webpage you were visiting before you came to our Site, pages of our Site that you visit, the time spent on those pages, information you search for on our Site, access times and dates, and other statistics. We use this information to monitor and analyze use of the Site and the Service and for the Site's technical administration, to increase our Site's functionality and user-friendliness, and to better tailor it to our visitors' needs. We also use this information to verify that visitors to the Site meet the criteria required to process their requests. We do not treat Log Data as Personal Information or use it in association with other Personal Information, though we may aggregate, analyze and evaluate such information for the same purposes as stated above regarding other Non-Identifying Information.

## 4\. Cookies

Like many websites, we use "cookies" to collect information. A cookie is a small data file that we transfer to your computer's hard disk for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies for two purposes. First, we utilize persistent cookies to save your registration ID and login password for future logins to the Site. Second, we utilize session ID cookies to enable certain features of the Site, to better understand how you interact with the Site and to monitor aggregate usage by Rover.com Users and web traffic routing on the Site. Unlike persistent cookies, session cookies are deleted from your computer when you log off from the Site and Service and then close your browser. Third party advertisers on the Site may also place or read cookies on your browser. You can instruct your browser, by changing its options, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit. If you do not accept cookies, however, you may not be able to use all portions of the Site or all functionality of the Service.

### DISCLOSURE SPECIFIC TO GOOGLE

Rover uses Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting, which is based on Google Display Advertising. Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting uses cookies. You can choose to opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and manage Google Display Network ads using Google Ads Settings. We use the information provided by this service (such as age, gender and interests) to improve the usability of the Site and Service, and to deliver more relevant content.

## 5\. Web Beacons

Our Web pages contain electronic images known as Web beacons (sometimes called single-pixel gifs) and are used along with cookies to compile aggregated statistics to analyze how our site is used and may be used in some of our emails to let us know which emails and links have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of our customer communications and marketing campaigns.

## 6\. Messages Sent Via a Rover.com Account

As part of the Service, Rover.com Users may communicate with Rover.com Members through use of the "Contact" feature on the site. Where Rover.com Users have selected the option of adding one or more email addresses to an online form, the message they create in the corresponding template will be sent from Rover.com to those email addresses on their behalf. These email addresses will be used only for the purpose of sending the email communication to the addressee.

Your friend may contact us at [support@rover.com](mailto:support@rover.com) to request that we remove this information from our database, and we will use reasonable efforts to remove the information.

You can import contacts from your email account address book to invite them to send you a recommendation. We collect the username and password for the email account you wish to import your contacts from and will only use it for that purpose only. By choosing to import your contacts, you consent to our access of your email address book. Your use of the “Contact” feature (or any other messaging feature) of the Site is subject to the Terms of Service. We have the right, but not the obligation, to review, save, edit, decline to transmit, and otherwise use such messages, including their contents, in our sole discretion. YOUR USE OF THE “CONTACT” OR ANY OTHER MESSAGING FEATURE OF THE SITE CONSTITUTES BOTH YOUR ACKNOWLEDGEMENT THAT MESSAGES SENT USING THESE FEATURES ARE NOT PRIVATE, AND YOUR CONSENT FOR US TO REVIEW, SAVE, EDIT, DECLINE TO TRANSMIT, AND OTHERWISE USE THE MESSAGES OR THEIR CONTENTS OR DISCLOSE THEIR CONTENTS TO THIRD PARTIES, IN OUR SOLE DISCRETION. 

## 7\. Phishing

Identity theft and the practice currently known as "phishing" are of great concern to Rover.com. Safeguarding information to help protect you from identity theft is a priority. We do not and will not, at any time, request your credit card information, your account ID, login password, or national identification numbers in a non-secure or unsolicited e-mail or telephone communication. For more information about phishing, visit the Federal Trade Commission's website at [http://www.ftc.gov](http://www.ftc.gov/).

## 8\. Information Sharing and Disclosure

Rover.com is designed to allow Members who have a home to host dogs ("Hosts"), Members who will travel to another Members home to watch pets ("Sitters"), and Members who wish to find care for their pets ("Pet Owners") to share information with one another in order to facilitate arranging stays and sittings. Listings posted by Hosts and Sitters, ratings and reviews of Hosts, Sitters and Pet Owners, and the Profile Information (as defined below) of Hosts and Pet Owners, are visible to any visitor to the site. If a Host or a Sitter and a Pet Owner enter into a confirmed transaction with one another (the Host accepts the Pet Owner's request, and the Pet Owner's payment details are collected and processed), then the Pet Owner and the Host's Identity Information are shared with each other in order to facilitate the reservation. In no event is a Pet Owner's Billing Information shared with their Host or Sitter.

**If you post any of your information to a public area of our Service, please be aware that it is no longer Personal Information for the purposes of this policy, and we or anyone else may use such information without restriction. If you provide access to Personal Information or other information, including your email address or name, to a limited set of other users through any of our privacy controls or other settings, please understand that Rover.com has no control over how others may collect, use, or disclose such information.**

## 9\. Rover.com Members and Users

When you register through the Site and submit your Personal Information to create a profile webpage, Rover.com Users will see your first name and last initial ("Required Member Identifiers"). You can choose what other Personal Information you provide as part of your profile ("Other Member Information") (together, your "Profile Information"). We will display your Profile Information in your profile page, elsewhere on the Site, and on third party sites (e.g., through the use of a Rover.com HTML "widget" or API). Any information you choose to provide as part of your profile should reflect how much you want other Rover.com Users to know about you. We recommend that you guard your anonymity and sensitive information and we encourage members to think carefully about what information about themselves they disclose in their profile pages. You can review and revise your profile information at any time.

If you post a listing, we may publish that listing anywhere on the Site and may enable third parties to publish your listing on their site through the use of an HTML "widget". We may also display the geographical location of your listing in the form of a map so that potential guests can see the general area and neighborhood of your listing, but your actual street address will not be disclosed until you enter into a confirmed transaction with another Rover.com Member. If you enter into a confirmed transaction with another Rover.com Member (that is, you request hosting or sitting from another Member, the other Member confirms your reservation, and your payment is processed, you will have access to that Member's Identity Information, and that Member will have access to your Identity Information. Note that Members will never have access to your Billing Information.

## 10\. Aggregate Information and Non-Identifying Information

We may share aggregated information that does not include Personal Information and we may otherwise share disclose Non-Identifying Information and Log Data with third parties for industry analysis, demographic profiling and other purposes. Any aggregated information shared in these contexts will not contain your Personal Information, unless such Personal Information is Non-Identifying Information.

## 11\. Third Party Service Providers

We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate, advertise and promote our Service, to provide the Service on our behalf, to perform Site-related services (e.g., without limitation, maintenance services, database management, web analytics and improvement of the Site's features) or to assist us in analyzing how our Site and Service are used. These third parties may have access to your Personal Information; if they do, this access is only so that they may perform these tasks on our behalf and they are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose. We may also provide Personal Information to our business partners or other trusted entities for the purpose of providing you with information on goods or services we believe will be of interest to you. You can, at any time, opt out of receiving such communications. We may use your Identity Information, alone or in conjunction with any content you submit to the Site, to advertise and promote the Service and the pet care services you provide (including without limitation, any photograph, words, pictures, or symbols), and may provide your Identity Information and/or your submitted content to third party service providers in connection with such advertising and promotion. For example, we may ask advertisers to display ads on third party websites which promote the pet care services you provide through Rover. With your consent, ads which we request such third parties to display may contain your name and contact information.

## 12\. Compliance with Laws and Law Enforcement

Rover.com cooperates with government and law enforcement officials and private parties to enforce and comply with the law. We will disclose any information about you to government or law enforcement officials or private parties as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate to respond to claims and legal process (including but not limited to subpoenas), to protect the property and rights of Rover.com or a third party, to protect the safety of the public or any person, in the event of a dispute, or to prevent or stop activity we may consider to be, or to pose a risk of being, any illegal, unethical or legally actionable activity.

## 13\. Business Transfers

Rover.com may sell, transfer or otherwise share some or all of its assets, including your Personal Information, in connection with a merger, acquisition, reorganization or sale of assets or in the event of bankruptcy.

## 14\. Changing or Deleting Your Information

All Members may review, update, or correct the Personal Information in their registration profile by contacting us at [support@rover.com](mailto:support@rover.com) or editing the relevant part of their profile. If you contact us, we will attempt to accommodate your request, including any request to deactivate your record in our system. See below for privacy contact information.

## 15\. Security

We have put in place physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online to protect the Personal Information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact us at [support@rover.com](mailto:support@rover.com).

We will attempt to make any legally required disclosures of any breach of the security, confidentiality, or integrity of your unencrypted electronically stored "personal data" (as defined in applicable state statutes on security breach notification) to you via email or conspicuous posting on this Site, insofar as consistent with (i) the legitimate needs of law enforcement or (ii) any measures necessary to determine the scope of the breach and restore the reasonable integrity of the data system.

## 16\. Links to Other Sites

Our Site contains links to other websites. If you choose to visit an advertiser by "clicking on" a banner ad or other type of advertisement, or click on another third party link, you will be directed to that third party's website. The fact that we link to a website or present a banner ad or other type of advertisement is not an endorsement, authorization or representation of our affiliation with that third party, nor is it an endorsement of their privacy or information security policies or practices. We do not exercise control over third party websites. These other websites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data or solicit personal information from you. Other sites follow different rules regarding the use or disclosure of the personal information you submit to them. We encourage you to read the privacy policies or statements of the other websites you visit.

## 17\. Our Policy Toward Children

We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 18; nor do we allow such persons to use our Site or Services. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with Personal Information without their consent, he or she should contact us at [support@rover.com](mailto:support@rover.com). If we become aware that a child under 18 has provided us with Personal Information, we will delete such information from our files.

## 18\. International Visitors

The Service is hosted in and provided from the United States. If you use our Service from the European Union or other regions with laws governing data collection and use that may differ from U.S. law, please note that you are transferring your personal data to the United States. The United States does not have the same data protection laws as the EU and some other regions. By providing your personal information, you consent to the transfer of your personal data to the United States and the use of your personal information in accordance with this policy.

## 19\. Contacting Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [support@rover.com](mailto:support@rover.com).
